CURRICULUM VITAE

ELECTRICAL AND TELECOMUNICATION ENGINEER

P.O. Box 20631 – 00100 NAIROBI 0712 322 226 Kings.bradley@gmail.com

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Bradley Kings Opundo

Nationality: Kenyan

ID No: 35678051

Language: English, Swahili & Luo

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a self-motivated, creative electrical and telecommunication engineering graduate who possesses interpersonal skills and a team player with hands-on experience.

I am hardworking, diligent and dedicated to innovate, integrate and build ingenious sustainable solutions in the Telecommunication, ICT and Energy sector, all qualities I put forward in everything I do.

I am an easy-going guy who enjoys challenging situations and diverse roles and am confident working with more experienced colleagues in the same field as well as another field. Most of all, I strive to cultivate a set of skills that make me an asset wherever I apply myself.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

- I like utilizing my acquired skills, knowledge and abilities in a department that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative, economical and flexible in duty.
- To work as part of a dynamic team that offers strategic plans in development.
- To apply and share my acquired knowledge, skills and experience in the electrical and telecommunication field.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Science Electrical and Telecommunication Engineering

Multimedia University of Kenya

Second Class Honors (Lower Division)

31/08/2016 - 17/12/2021

- Learnt Power systems, Electrical Machine Design, Radio wave propagation and planning, Data Communication, AC Transmission systems and HVDC, Digital Electronics and Control systems as part of the course work.
- I also learnt Microwaves in final year. The main aspects of the course were; antennas and waveguides, radio wave propagation, microwave link planning and models for communication channels for microwaves. Digital data transmission, protocol architecture, computer networks, network media and devices for telecommunication
- Specialized in Protection and switchgear, Power Station Practice, Wireless communication and Satellite communication in final year.
- Did a final year project on microprocessor-based access and monitoring using NFC. The idea was to have a provision for wireless payment and a database for profiling of individuals of interest e.g. trouble makers by embracing modern technology in the current billing and access control systems in Kenyan stadiums.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Kanga High School

Grade attained: B+

02/2012 - 11/2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Independent Contractor, Appen (freelance)

06/2021 - Present

Appen provides or improves data used for the development of machine learning and artificial intelligence products. Data types include speech and natural language data, image and video data, text and alphanumeric data and relevance data to improve search and social media engines

Responsibilities:

I am an independent contractor providing services for Appen Itd by providing and improving data to train and develop Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence (AI) products. Services I offer include:

- Data collection tasks that are used in wide variety of applications
 data annotation, multimedia, sentiment analysis and search engine result evaluation.
- Social media evaluation

Conducted research, performed evaluation and feedback of web search engine results of pre-defined queries helping technology companies craft a fun and useful experience for people who are searching for information around the world.

Comparing a catalog of products to the products listed on a particular given website.

Transcription

Reviewing lists of words that have been transcribed phonetically by software or rating and comparing audio statements against pre-transcribed data, correcting any mistakes

Internet Analyst

Providing feedback on search results, advertisements, and web page content

Volunteer work, Erdemann Property

02/2022

A limited Liability Company specializing in property development. EPL operates under the Investment Promotion Centre and was pioneered by a Chinese investor, Mr. Zeyun Yang together with a dedicated team of young professionals who have been very instrumental in the company's transformation over the years

Responsibilities:

- Electrical construction work.
- Electrical wiring
- Conduit works
- Dropping and piping
- Any electrical duties assigned

Contact: Chege -0736141715

Attachee, Mehta Electricals Ltd.

02/2021 - 04/2021

Mehta Electricals is East Africa's leading Electrical and ICT contractor. They provide a wide range of electrical contracting services

to industrial, commercial and institutional clients across the continent.

Responsibilities:

- Electrical appliance fitting
- Conduit works
- Cabling
- Servicing cables
- Wall fittings
- Piping

- Electronic troubleshooting
- WAN, LAN and WLAN protocols
- Cabling standards (electrical and network)
- Network optimization

Contact: Rana Gurav -0786867052 Contact: Dennis Ochieng -0727893762

Attachee, Kenya Airports Authority 05/2019 – 08/2019

Kenya Airports Authority (KAA) provides facilitative infrastructure for aviation services between Kenya and the outside world.

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting and repair of electrical installations including power and lighting installations in buildings, airport street lights, flood lights, taxiway lights and runway lights.
- Maintenance of electrical facilities including control of the generator, electrical supply units and main circuit breakers.
- Installation, repair and service of PABX and associated telephone equipment including telephone networks, telephone lines and telephone handset receivers.
- Maintenance of VHF radio transceivers and Television Network.
- Control and maintenance of the Baggage Handling System, Passenger Boarding bridges and the luggage conveyor belts.
- Control of the PLC motor control system that would remotely control various electrical and electronic equipment.
- Conduction of preventive and curative maintenance on sites
- Monitoring of network alarms and escalation of the alarms to proper channels

Contact: David M. Wameyo -0733801397

Bed and Breakfast Manager (AIRBNB)

12/2015 - 11/2016

Hosted more than 500 guests across the world and managed to maintain a 5 Star Rating on the Airbnb app.

Responsibilities:

- Confirming bookings and communicating with guests.
- Taking care of check-ins and check-outs.
- Arranging tours and travel for guests around the country
- Scheduling and managing cleanings and maintenance work.
- Maintaining listings on Airbnb app and other rental platforms such as booking.com

Contact: Eva Adongo -0733 684 322

SKILLS ACQUIRED

Engineering Design

Providing direction at all levels for creating company documentation standards, strategic engineering design/planning, vendor selection and budgeting. This including adherence to quality assurance & quality control standards.

Analytical and problem-solving and good time management

ability to distill key insights from a large amount of information to form distinct choices while evaluating risks. Ability to think creatively to generate new ideas to solve problems.

- Carrying out site surveys and installations of various telecommunication and IT services and equipment.
- Carry out support and preventive maintenance services to various clients.
- Providing technical guidance to clients and other team's members.
- Customer facing.
- Finding creative solutions to the challenges of network design, data service requirements and internet and network signaling protocols.
- Analyzing and interpreting data.
- Working to tight timescales as part of a team.
- Planning & organizing skills
- Root cause analysis skills
- Delivering results & meeting customer
- Online research negotiation & argumentation skills
- · possession of high expectations
- Presentation & communication skill
- Applying expertise & technology
- Knowledge Sharing skills
- Good writing and reporting skills

VOLUNTEER WORK

A member of the Rays of Hope Foundation, a Non-profit organization formed by youth focused on helping the less fortunate.

Worked with Grace community Education Centre (GCEC), a community-based organization situated in Ngomongo, Kasarani that offers free pre-primary and primary education to the orphaned and needy children

https://www.instagram.com/raysofhopefoundation/?hl=en

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned in regard to my competence for the job at hand;

1. Name: Mr Koech Edwin Kipyegon Position:

Head of Department

Electrical and Telecommunication Engineering Organization: Multimedia University of Kenya

Contact: <u>ekipyegon@gmail.com</u> +254(0)0722109886

P.O BOX 15653-00503, NAIROBI

2. Name: Mr. Rana Gurav Position: Site Engineer

Electrical Engineering

Organization: Mehta Electricals Ltd

Contact: +254(0)7867052

P.O BOX 39977-00623, NAIROBI

3. Name: Mr. Dennis Ochieng

Position: Site foreman/supervisor

Electrical Engineering

Organization: Mehta Electricals Ltd

Contact: +254(0)727893762

P.O BOX 39977-00623, NAIROBI

4. Name: Mr. Patrick Ekwar Etiir Position: Electronics Technician

Organization: Kenya Airports Authority

Contact: ekwarpatrick@gmail.com +254(0) 723920752

5. Name: David M. Wameyo

Position: Electrical Technician

Organization: Kenya Airports Authority

Contact: +254(0)733801397 or +254(0)722417122

6. Name: Eva Lois Adongo

Owner of Eva's Place (Airbnb)

https://www.airbnb.com/users/show/564600

International Trade and Digital Finance

Tel: 0722684322